{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1.Reason for gradual decrease in cross-sectional area of the Spiral casing of the Francis turbine from the entrance to the tip is:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To ensure constant velocity ",
        "b": "To prevent loss of efficiency of the turbine due to friction",
        "c": "To prevent leakage from the turbine",
        "d": "To reduce material used, hence making it economical"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2.……………………. is defined as the ratio between the power available at the shaft to the power supplied by water at the inlet",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Hydraulic efficiency",
        "b": "Volumetric efficiency",
        "c": "Mechanical efficiency",
        "d": "Overall efficiency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3.…………………… is defined as the ratio between the power produced by runner to the power supplied by water at the inlet",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Hydraulic efficiency",
        "b": "Volumetric efficiency",
        "c": "Mechanical efficiency",
        "d": "Overall efficiency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "4.……………………………. is defined as the ratio between total quantity of water over runner blades to total quantity of water supplied to turbine",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Hydraulic efficiency",
        "b": "Volumetric efficiency",
        "c": "Mechanical efficiencyanswer3",
        "d": "Overall efficiency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "5.……………………………. is defined as the ratio between the power available at the shaft of the turbine to the power produced by the runner",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Hydraulic efficiency",
        "b": "Volumetric efficiency",
        "c": "Mechanical efficiency",
        "d": "Overall efficiency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "6.……………………………… converts the dynamic pressure (kinetic energy) into static pressure",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Draft tube",
        "b": "Conduits",
        "c": "Penstock",
        "d": "Runner"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "7.Hydraulic turbine converts hydro energy into mechanical by using ……………. of water",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Potential energy",
        "b": "Kinetic energy",
        "c": "both (a) and (b)",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "8.Cavitation occurs at ……………………….",
      "answers": {
        "a": "High pressure",
        "b": "Low pressure",
        "c": "Atmospheric pressure",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "9.In cavitation, the material fails due to ………………………….",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Erosion",
        "b": "Creep",
        "c": "Impact load",
        "d": "Fracture"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "10.In mixed flow turbines, the water enters the runner ………………… and comes out ……………….",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Axially, radially",
        "b": "Radially, axially",
        "c": "Both (a) and (b)",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
